# Vianney Celestin Kabamba

Manchester, UK • vianneyk@hotmail.co.uk • 07762761661

### Professional Profile

I am an enthusiastic developer who takes on extensive research to overcome any problem I may encounter and I am always willing to learn new skills. I am bilingual and currently attending the Coding Bootcamp at the University of Manchester which I am projected to finish the program in May 2021. Before transitioning into web development, I diligently worked as a field service engineer throughout England, Scotland, wales and France. While in the filed engineering industry I found myself enjoying the technical and computer driven aspects of the office which lead me to follow my true passion for full stack development.

## **Work Experience**

The University of Manchester Coding Boot Camp Full Stack Developer - Trainee, 10/2020 to present

- Learned full stack technologies through a dynamic web developing curriculum which includes HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Java, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Git and more.
- Worked with teammates to tackle complex projects and tasks, and get hands-on training through experimental learning opportunities.
- Took my new learned skills to the next level on challenging projects, building a portfolio of applications and projects to showcase my knowledge.

Club Liv - Manchester, City Centre

Assistant General Manager, 8/2018 to 1/2020

Hold full accountability for promoting and marketing the business in line with health and safety standards. Administer budgets and maintain financial/statistical records. Oversee day-to-day responsibilities such as supervising/maintaining inventory of stocks at the bar, performing any repairs, managing staff weekly wages, paying invoices on time, and updating all respective licenses.

### Selected Contributions:

- Ensured accurate diagnosis and swift resolution of all customer complaints and enquiries.
- Reduced stock loss due to human error by recruiting, supervising, and training staff training on weekly basis.

Fanatics – Manchester, Ancoats

Field & Commissioning Engineer, 3/2018 to 6/2018

Oversaw system installation, commissioning, and decommissioning. Delivered robust on-site support to customers and executed preventative maintenance work within deadline according to the highest standards. Maintained accurate records and submitted service-related reports to senior management in a timely manner.

Continued...

## Vianney Celestin Kabamba ••• Page 2

#### Selected Contributions:

- Devised, implemented, and promoted best practices while ensuring constant reliability to production by liaising with the engineering team.
- Minimised delays in events by having a tested backup EPOS equipment during emergencies.

Robotik Technology – Cheshire, Daresbury Field Service Engineer, 1/2018 to 3/2018

Carried out installation of pill dispensing machine in different pharmacies across UK in adherence with health and safety regulations. Performed PPM, reactive calls, and mechanical works on customers' sites. Successfully fixed repairs first time while providing updates to clients and service desk on regular basis. Maintained a disciplined and flexible approach to all client relations.

### Selected Contributions:

- Discovered a new technology to improve way of manufacturing trays for robot/pill dispenser.
- Met performance criteria according to site SLAs while collaborating with the department.

Betfred – Warrington, Birchwood Field Service Engineer, 5/2017 to 12/2017

Installed hubs, adaptors, splitters, video leads, and switches to ensure better transmission of video image from decoders to raspberry pies circuits. Supervised Internet Protocol (IP) configuration to gather and display data on a screen. Assumed and maintained full accountability for resolving all technical issues. Trained customers regarding maintenance of new installation system.

### Selected Contributions:

- Completed de-installation of old server and installation/programming of a new server in minimum time.
- Transformed existing scar leads into cat5 cables and utilised RJ45 connectors to install a new network cable system.

# **Educational Background**

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics & Electrical Engineering
Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, England
Higher National Diploma, Electronics, Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester, England

Vocational Certificate of Education, Electronics Engineering, The Manchester College, Manchester, England

t i i

**Qualified First Aider**